mountsinai.org 2019-08-01

# Privacy Policy | Mount Sinai - New York

**PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY BEFORE USING THE SERVICES**

This website is owned and operated by Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai (“MOUNT SINAI” or “we”, “us” or “our”). This Privacy Policy applies to MOUNT SINAI’s website located at mountsinaihealth.org as well as all other websites owned, operated, licensed, or controlled by MOUNT SINAI, and certain affiliate websites that are hyperlinked to the foregoing (collectively, the “Websites”). This Privacy Policy also applies to all mobile applications offered under the MOUNT SINAI name that do not have a separate privacy policy or that link to this Privacy Policy (the “Apps”). Collectively, the Websites and Apps are referred to in this Privacy Policy as the “Services.”

BY ACCESSING OR USING THE SERVICES, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND THE TERMS OF USE. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY OR THE TERMS OF USE, DO NOT ACCESS OR USE THE SERVICES.

This Privacy Policy applies to the use of the Services and the information provided by and obtained from users of the Services. MOUNT SINAI maintains a separate policy in connection with the Health Portability and Accountability Act (“HIPAA”) that can be viewed [here](http://www.mountsinai.org/about-us/compliance/hipaa-privacy-and-security-compliance-program).

**INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT**

MOUNT SINAI collects two types of information: (1) personally identifiable information that you provide voluntarily when you access certain features of the Services as noted below in this Privacy Policy, and (2) generalized usage information that we collect automatically as you access the Services.

**Information That You Provide Voluntarily on the Websites.** MOUNT SINAI collects personally identifiable information that you enter into data fields on the Websites. For example, when you access the “Request an Appointment” feature via a Website, you may be asked for certain personally identifiable information, including but not limited to your name and email address. Other features of the Websites may ask for other personally identifiable information necessary for the proper functionality of such features. If you decline to provide certain information while using the Websites, you may not be able to use or participate in some or all of the features offered through the Websites. We may retain email and other communications that you send us in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests, and improve the Services. MOUNT SINAI also collects and stores personally identifiable information that you enter during chats and that you enter into pre-chat surveys.

**Information That You Provide Voluntarily on the Apps.** MOUNT SINAI collects personally identifiable information that you enter into data fields on the Apps. For example, when you access the “Request an Appointment” feature via an App, you may be asked for certain personally identifiable information, including but not limited to your name and email address. Other features of the Apps may ask for other personally identifiable information necessary for the proper functionality of such features. If you decline to provide certain information while using an App, you may not be able to use or participate in some or all of the features offered through the App. MOUNT SINAI also collects and stores personally identifiable information that you enter during chats and that you enter into pre-chat surveys.

**Usage Information That Is Automatically Collected on the Websites.** When you access the Websites, MOUNT SINAI may collect certain generalized information without your actively providing such information. This information may include, for example, your browser type, your operating system, and your IP address. This information may be collected using various technologies including cookies, as explained below.

**Usage Information That Is Automatically Collected on the Apps.** When you access the Apps, MOUNT SINAI may collect certain generalized information without your actively providing such information. This information may include, for example, the type of mobile device you are using and your mobile operating system. When you access certain Apps, we may assign to you a unique analytics tracking identification number (ID). MOUNT SINAI uses this ID to collect generalized information about your interaction with the Apps in order to improve your experience of the Apps. Certain Apps may also use location services to provide location-based features. If you enable location services on your device and grant permission for such Apps to access this feature, we may collect your location via GPS in order to provide you with such features.

**HOW WE USE INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT**

MOUNT SINAI uses the personally identifiable information that it collects to ensure the proper functionality of the Services across various devices, to process user inquiries and respond to user requests, to analyze usage trends, to improve the Services, and to develop new Services.

MOUNT SINAI employs a variety of online security measures to safeguard and keep your information private.

MOUNT SINAI processes personally identifiable information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

MOUNT SINAI does not share your personally identifiable information with third parties without your consent, except for third-party suppliers that perform essential business or administrative services for us (for example, our web hosting provider). MOUNT SINAI provides these suppliers only with the information they need to perform such services and asks that they either comply with this Privacy Policy or maintain comparable privacy policies that protect your personally identifiable information.

MOUNT SINAI stores certain personally identifiable information using Amazon Web Services, a third-party hosting service provider. Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to Amazon Web Services, and MOUNT SINAI makes no warranty regarding the privacy, integrity, or security of any information stored by Amazon Web Services. Details regarding the data protection and privacy practices observed by Amazon Web Services can be found here: <http://aws.amazon.com/security/>.

When you download and access the Apps, MOUNT SINAI may send you push notifications to alert you of important information. If you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, you may disable them at the mobile device level.

**COOKIES**

MOUNT SINAI may place small data files, called "cookies," on your computer or other device. Cookies are a standard web technology that allow us to both store and retrieve login information on a user's system. These cookies automatically identify your browser to our server whenever you interact with a service provided on the Services. Cookies can store your preferences via a password you select to access a website. Cookies also help us review website traffic patterns and improve the Websites. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you usually can change your browser setting to prevent the acceptance of cookies, although this may prevent you from using some of the features of the Services. It is important to note that information collected through cookies is not linked to any personally identifiable information.

**THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES**

In order to provide you with other valuable information, MOUNT SINAI may provide links to third-party websites outside the MOUNT SINAI Health System network. MOUNT SINAI exercises no authority over, and does not necessarily endorse, such third-party websites.

These destination links are provided only for your convenience and, as such, you access them at your own risk. However, MOUNT SINAI wishes to assure the integrity of the Services and their destination links, so any comments pertaining to the Services or any websites accessed through our links are greatly appreciated. Comments can be submitted to webfeedback@mountsinai.org.

**LEGAL MATTERS**

MOUNT SINAI reserves the right to comply with the law and to release personally identifiable information relating to any user of the Services (i) if we reasonably believe that the user is in violation of our Terms of Use or other published guidelines or is engaged in illegal activity, (ii) to release information in response to court and governmental orders, other enforceable requests from government entities, civil subpoenas, discovery requests and otherwise as required by law, (iii) if we reasonably believe that such release is required to protect the rights, property, safety or security of any of our users or the public, or (iv) to respond to an emergency.

**CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

The Services are not intended for use by children under the age of 18. In accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), MOUNT SINAI does not knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without parental consent. When we do receive information (with parental consent) from users under the age of 13, we will not share their personally identifiable information with third parties, regardless of their stated preference given at registration, in compliance with COPPA.

**ACCESSIBILITY**

The Services are designed to be accessible to visitors with disabilities, and to comply with federal guidelines concerning accessibility. We welcome your comments. If you have suggestions on how to make the Services more accessible, please contact us at [webfeedback@mountsinai.org](mailto:webfeedback@mountsinai.org).

**CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

MOUNT SINAI may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. We encourage you to check this page for any changes to the Privacy Policy and for new versions thereof. By continuing to access, browse, and/or use the Services, you agree to accept any posted revised terms.
